Okay, so in this video
then, we are going to discuss
the Agile Life Cycle
and the Agile Manifesto.
Now, in a couple of the earlier videos,
we have mentioned Agile, right?
We've talked about Agile, but
some of you may have never
really come across an Agile
environment before, right?
So, for a benefit of those of you that
have never come across an Agile or an
Agile environment, let me just give you
just some of the basic principles first,
before we talk about the Agile life cycle
and the manifesto.
So Agile originally started off in the
software development industry where
traditionally, right, in a traditional
predictive environment, right,
where you have many, many different
phases, right, so a waterfall type of
methodology, right, or the SDLC, as it was
called, right, the software
development lifecycle.
Right.
So in a traditional IT environment,
traditional project environment using the
software development lifecycle,
right, the general procedure was you know,
it may be, you're doing a big software
implementation.
It may be an 18-month, two-year-long
project, right?
You get your requirements at the beginning
of the project, you get your requirements,
all of your requirements at the beginning
of the project from your customer,
right?
Then you spend the next 18-month,
two years basically developing this system
and then you deliver this system to the
customer.
And of course, the customer was never
happy.
And why were they not happy?
Right.
Well, because you are delivering a system
based on requirements from two years ago.
So already what you're delivering is out
of date, right?
The world has changed since then.
Things have happened.
Things have changed.
And then secondly, the customer don't
always know exactly what requirements they
need, especially we're talking about big,
huge system implementation.
Right?
They don't know exactly every
single piece of requirement
that they need, you know,
right at the beginning.
And plus, they're going to be delivering
in two years' time.
they don't know exactly what you need in
two years' time.
And that's where this agile environment
came in, right, where you are actually
delivering something to the customer every
couple of weeks, right?
Or, you know, every two to
four weeks, you're actually
delivering something
of value to the customer.
So the customer is involved throughout the
project, right?
So typically what happens then is you get
your requirements from your customer at
the beginning of the project or the
beginning of a release, right?
In an agile environment, an agile project
is known as a release.
and typically a release is three to nine
months.
I mean, it doesn't have to be,
but typically.
And then within a release, you have many,
many different sprints, right?
Or many different iterations in an Agile.
Those iterations are known as sprints.
And typically a sprint is two to four
weeks.
So you get your requirements,
which are known as user
stories at the beginning, you
know, as many as possible.
Then you prioritize these user stories to
create what's known as a product backlog.
So backlog then now is a list of
prioritise.
requirements prioritize user stories.
Now at each sprint then, the team is going
to select these high priority user
stories, these high
priority items, and that is
what they're going to
deliver in each sprint.
And then at the end of
each sprint, you're going
to deliver something
of value to the customer.
So now if there's a change, either
internally or externally, new requirements
come in, like new user stories come in,
right?
Some are higher priority than others, the
whole product, backlog gets reprioritized.
So you're constantly, constantly then
delivering something to the customer every
couple of weeks, something of value to the
customer.
And so Agile then takes into consideration
constantly changing business environment.
As things are changing,
right, your requirements can
change, what you're delivering
is going to be changing.
And basically responding to change.
That's a whole one of the principles
behind Agile.
So this then here, this diagram here is a
typical agile type of life cycle.
Right now, there's three specific roles,
right, that I want to
mention regarding agile.
First, you have this role called the
product owner.
Now, the product owner
represents the customer
or think of them as a
voice of the customer.
They represent the customer.
Then you have the agile team, and they're
a cross-functional team that is basically
delivering the work, delivering to the
customer.
And then you have the team facilitator
here.
The team facilitator is for all intents
and purposes, the court project manager.
In an agile environment, there is no real
project manager.
They're known as a team facilitator.
A project manager is usually a command and
control project manager.
The team facilitator, a servant leader.
And we'll discuss the difference between
those two roles in a separate video.
Now, at the beginning of a
project then, you've got the
product owner, the Agile
team, and the team facilitator.
They get together, they
get the requirements
from the customer and
other key stakeholders.
So beginning of an agile project meaning
an agile release, right?
You get your requirements from the
customer.
Now, the product toner then
is going to prioritize those
list of requirements or
those list of user stories.
It's a product toner who's going to
prioritize.
And that prioritized list of user stories
is known as a product backlog.
And then for each sprint, the Agile Team
now is going to select the high priority
user stories, along with the product owner
as well.
They're going to select these high
priority user stories, a selection of them.
And that's what they're going to deliver
in the sprint.
That is what they're going to deliver in
each sprint.
They're not delivering
the entire product backlog,
just a selection of
these high priority items.
So each sprint then is two to four weeks,
and during those two to four weeks,
that is what they're going to deliver.
That's what they're going to be working
on.
Now, on a daily basis, each
day, you have what's known
as a daily stand-up meeting,
also known as a daily scrum.
You might see that term there.
And the team facilitator
is the one that is
generally hosting the
daily stand-up meeting.
And it's time boxed 10 to 15 minutes,
no more than that.
And each team member
is going to be asking three
questions, or rather
addressing three questions.
and three questions are, what did I
accomplish yesterday, what am I going to
work on today, and what impediments are
there, what issues are there?
And if there are any issues, any
impediments, then the team facilitator is
going to take that offline and then try
and resolve those impediments,
try and remove those impediments,
blockers, or whatever issues they have.
So that's on a daily basis.
Now, at the end of the sprint, right, you
have what's known as
a sprint review meeting.
right so and that is for the for the team
to deliver the product to the product
owner remember the product owner
represents a customer right so they are
delivering the product to the product
owner and the product owner is going to
either prove it or reject it and that
after the sprint review meeting right
there's a sprint retrospective right
another meeting sprint retrospective and a
sprint retrospective is basically a
lessons learned meeting that's really all
it is it's a lessons
learned meeting, it is also
the iteration or the sprint
closeout meeting, right?
So where you'd be discussing first,
what went right, what went wrong,
right, and then you'd also be talking
about preparation now for the next sprint.
So this typically then is an agile life
cycle.
Now, let me introduce also the Agile
Manifesto, right?
So the Agile Manifesto, right,
so this was developed by, you know,
the agile authors, right?
There were basically 17 software
developers that really came up with this
right at the beginning right when Agile
was developed.
And the Agile Manifesto contains four
paired values and 12 principles.
Now, don't memorize these.
You don't need to memorize
these, but just have a
decent understanding of
them more than anything else.
So the four paired values are individual
and interaction over processes and tools,
right?
Basically what that is saying is,
We don't just want to blindly follow
procedures and blindly use tools that have
been instructed to us.
No, individuals and interaction,
that is more important.
We need to understand.
Remember, we're delivering value to the
customer.
So we need to interact.
We need to collaborate.
So that is more important rather than
blindly following procedures.
Working software over comprehensive
documentation.
Again, working software
is a primary measure
of success rather than
blindly documenting.
Now, that does not mean that we ignore
documentation.
No, all the same, I mean, you still have
to document.
Just like you still have to follow
procedures and tools, processes and tools,
but individuals and interaction is more
important.
Same with working software is more
If the software isn't
working, then that's what we
should be focused on rather
than tons of documentation.
documentation can come afterwards.
Customer collaboration over contract
negotiation.
Again, we're delivering value to the
customer.
So we need to collaborate
with the customer
rather than focusing
what's on the contract.
And the way we should be negotiating the
contract, the way we would negotiate a
contract should be open so
that we can collaborate with
a customer, responding to
change over following a plan.
That is a whole principle behind Agile is
responding to change.
Of course, you need a plan.
You always have to have a plan,
but the plans can change.
So those are the four paired values.
Now let's quickly go through the 12
principles.
And again, you don't need to know
all these 12 principles in detail, right?
Just have a basic, decent understanding.
And the whole thing about any of these
principles is people work together.
Collaboration is the key.
That is kind of like the key throughout
the whole of Agile and pretty much the
whole of project, the whole of the PMP
exam now, right?
Interaction and collaboration.
Right.
So highest priority is satisfying the
customer.
That's the number one priority,
right?
We want to add value.
Remember, PMI are now value driven as
opposed to process driven.
We want to add value to give value to the
customer.
Right.
So highest priority, satisfy the customer.
Welcome changing
requirements, as I mentioned,
deliver working software's
primary measure of success.
Business people and developers must work
together.
So again, collaboration must work
Building projects around motivated
individuals, right?
So we're going to be talking about the
different requirements of the team,
of a project team, different skill sets of
the agile project team.
Team needs to be motivated, right?
So more about that on a separate video.
Most efficient and effective methods,
of conveying information is face-to-face,
right?
Now, when this was developed, this is
originally developed, I believe,
2001, right?
Face-to-face is usually the best form of
communication.
Obviously, that's not always possible in
this day and age, especially, you know,
with the whole COVID situation,
right?
But face-to-face does not always necessarily
mean that you are in the same room.
Face-to-face, I mean, that would be ideal,
obviously, but face-to-face can obviously
also mean conference call, video
conferencing, and so and so forth.
Primary measure is of success,
is working software, as I've mentioned.
And also this one, constant pace,
right?
That is something that is very important
in Agile, not like a traditional project
management where some weeks we're putting
in tons of overtime, 60, 70 hours a week,
some weeks are the low.
And depending on milestones and where we
are on the project.
No, the whole idea, or one
of the principles of Agile is
all resources should be
utilized at the optimum level.
So, team members should be constant pace.
They should be being utilized.
Their skill sets, their utilization should
be at the most optimum level.
Continuous attention to excellence,
right?
So that comes with experience,
That is naturally part of agile.
Simplicity, right?
So software coding should be at the
simplest level, right?
Not make anything complicated.
Best architecture comes on
self-organization.
team.
Again, we'll talk about self-organizing
teams in a separate video, right?
And team reflects on how to become more
effective, reflection.
That is basically lessons learnt,
right, which is done through the
retrospective, right, the retrospective
meeting at the end of the project.
Okay, so this was just
basically then an introduction to
Agile, right, the Agile Life
Cycle and the Agile Manifesto.